Kirill Shaplyko

Email: k.shaplyko@gmail.com

Skype: k.shaplyko Github: Baltazore

LinkedIn: Kirill Shaplyko Twitter: _baltazore Address: Minsk, Belarus

OVERVIEW

I am a web developer with extensive knowledge and experience in Ruby and JavaScript. My most recent experience has been as a Ember.js front-end developer at Mercedes-Benz USA.

You can find some of my work on Github profile. My recent technological interests and passions include the Ember.js, React.js, and Vue.js front-end frameworks, and experimenting with writing back-end services in Elixir.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance and Consulting

Software Developer 06.2015 - current, Remote

- Refactoring and optimizing large legacy codebases.
- ► Communicating with clients and gathering requirements.
- ► Project planning, creating roadmaps.
- ► Teaching and mentoring.
- Working on the deployments tasks.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, AWS, Heroku, Ember.js

Mercedes-Benz USA

Ember.js Developer, 08.2015 - 05.2017, Remote

- ► Front-end engineer responsible for development application using Ember.js.
- ► Working on the adapting legacy APIs and new JSONAPI services in single application.
- ► Developing the dealer portal for the Sales team.
- Writing full automated test suite.

GameHouse

Software Developer, 11.2013 - 05.2015, Remote

- ► Full stack engineer responsible for development application using Ruby on Rails, NodeJS, MongoDB, Redis, Angular.js.
- Working on the deployments tasks. Learning Ansible and Docker for building container based hosts.
- ► Developing the advertisement platform for the mobile devices.
- ▶ Brainstorm and prototype the new approach for some parts of the application.
- Writing specs and cucumber scenarios for integration tests for our API endpoints.

RubyRoid Labs

Software Developer, 09.2013 - 01.2015, Remote

- Full stack engineer responsible for development application using Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, Redis, Angular.js, Elasticsearch.
- Document generation system. The project includes document generation, task management for Police Department, Hospitals, ect.

Itransition

Ruby on Rails Developer, 08.2012 - 09.2013, Minsk, Belarus

Mobile advertising platform for back-end, front-end and mobile clients API for iOS and Android. The project is intended to increase sales for businesses by providing discounts.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, MySQL, Redis, Sidekiq, Faye, Pushover.

► Online auction system. Full auction workflow support (from creating to send notification about winnign beds). Dealing with admin panel, server back-end for real-time bid system.

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, Redis, MySQL, Faye, MongoDB, Rescue

► Social Media Aggregation System. It aggregates data by keywords from Facebook, Twitter, Sysomos (15+ servises), Google News, Google Blogs, Youtube, Google Images and Vocus (Print media and Blogspot). Dealing with main aggregation gateways, alert system (sms, email), report system (pdf, plain text, html).

Technologies: Ruby on Rails, MySQL, Facebook API, Twitter API, Klout API, Elasticsearch

EDUCATION

Belarussian State of Informatics and Radioelectronics

B.S. in Computer Science, May 2014

TECHNOLOGY FOCUS

Programming Languages: Ruby, JavaScript, Elixir

Web Frameworks: Ruby on Rails, Sintra, Node.js, Phoenix

Frontend Web Frameworks: *Ember.js*, Angular.js

DevOps: AWS (EC2, S3, Route53), Heroku, Chef, Ansible, Capistrano, Docker

Operating Systems: Linux (Ubuntu, CoreOS), *Mac OS X* **Programming Editors/IDEs:** vim, emacs, tmux, VS Code

Source Code Control: Git, Mercurial, Subversion

Databases: PostgreSQL 8/9, MySQL 4/5, MongoDB, Redis, Elasticsearch

Other technologies: AMQP (RabbitMQ), Resque, Sidekiq